Guide to the Jarvis-Robinson Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Jarvis-Robinson Family Acquisition
  - Autograph - Charles Tiffany and cancelled stamps (Box 26)
  - Berlise business papers (Box 26)
  - Bookplates (Box 26)
  - Bookplates C.L.F. Robinson and signed proofs (Box 26)
  - Business cards (Box 26)
  - Calling cards (misc.) (Box 26)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 26)
  - Colt, Caldwell M. - calling cards (Box 26)
  - Coat of Arms; Colt history plus others including Cushman (Box 26)
  - C.L.F. Robinson coat of arms - 4 signed copies (Box 26)
  - Concert program and playbills - Europe 1870s (Box 26)
  - CT Historical Society (Box 26)
  - Ephemera, 3 (Box 26)
  - Ephemera, 2 (Box 27)
  - Currency (Box 27)
  - Furniture Auction Catalogue, 1912 (Box 27)
  - Inventories Fragments (Box 27)
  - Heart's-Eare pamphlet KL Connor (Box 27)
  - Invitation - printed (Box 27)
  - Map of Hartford (printed), 1868 (Box 27)
  - Menus - manuscript and printed (Box 27)
  - Poetry (anonymous or unidentified) (Box 27)
  - Social announcements (weddings, balls, etc.) (Box 27)
  - Stationery, some with pictorial letterhead (Box 27)
  - Stationery (Box 28)
  - Stock certificates (miscellaneous - obsolete) (Box 28)
  - American Red Cross, knitting instruction etc. (World War I) (Box 28)
  - American Red Cross (Box 28)
  - Colt residence Hartford CT (Box 28)
  - "Attentat" "Diaboligal de Suicide" (Box 28)
  - Badenblatt frer Wildbad (Box 28)
  - Bellean Cemetery (Box 28)
  - Chateau Thierry and Bellean Woods assorted news articles re battles, 1918-1929 (Box 28)
  - Bordeaux, Henry Le Retours de Innocents (Box 28)
  - Brown, Howard N. Sermon in King's Chapel #71 "Men who Did Not Come Back", 1919 April 25 (Box 28)
  - Brunswick and Albany Railroad Co. coupons (Box 28)
  - Buckingham House: Pamphlet Brochure: Mystic Seaport, Mystic, CT (Box 28)
  - Church of the Good Shepherd, 2 (Box 28)
  - Printed Matter and Ephemera
    - Newport, RI Assembly Nov. 28 admission ticket (on verso "Queen of Spades"), 1791-1792 (Box 28)
    - St. James Church (Hartford?) (Box 28)
    - Colonial Dames of America, In Memoriam Elizabeth Hart Colt, 1905 (Box 28)
    - Colonial Dames, CT In Memoriam Mrs. Samuel Colt, 1905 (Box 28)
    - Elizabeth Colt, Program of Musical, 1870 January 8 (Box 28)
    - Elizabeth Colt, Program of Musical Evening, "To Mrs. C.N.B.", 1869 January 24 (Box 28)
    - Colt's Patent Firearms Manufacturing Company "List of Contractors" (Box 28)
    - Colt Firearms Manufacturing Company newspaper articles regarding strike, C.L.F. Robinson, president of Colt firearms (Box 28)
    - Col. C.L.F. Robinson - Colt Firearms, newspaper articles regarding Colt Firearms Manufacturing (Box 28)
    - Colt's Patent Firearms Manufacturing Company Death of C.L.F. Robinson, 1916 (Box 28)
    - Colt's Patent Arms Manufacturing Company (Box 28)
    - Colt's Willow Ware Manufacturing Company (Box 28)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution Elizabeth Colt's Membership Diploma, 1893 (Box 28)
    - News article regarding dispatch ship named after "Dauntless" New York Herald, 1917 August 5 (Box 28)
    - "Dauntless" (yacht) (Box 29)
    - Dauntless, Bill of Sale and Certificate, 1879, 1882 (Box 29)
    - Dos Cabezas Mines Ltd. Stock Certif. (Box 29)
    - Duncan, Isadora. Dance Recital, Rubayat of Omar Khayyam (Box 29)
    - Farmington Players, Connecticut (Box 29)
    - Field, Cyrus West, 25th Anniversary of Atlantic Cable Invitation, 1879 March 10 (Box 29)
    - Ford's Hotel, Richmond, VA (Box 29)
    - Grand Illumination du Colysee au feu de Bengals...par M. Athanase Morazzi, 1868 April 2 (Box 29)
    - Hamlin, William., engraving of George Washington (Box 29)
    - Hammond, C.S. and Co. "American Front in France" map, 1918 March 31 (Box 29)
    - Hart House Old Saybrook HS newspaper article, Hartford Courant (Box 29)
    - Hartford, Conn. Mayor's reception First Air Mail flight from Brainard Field, 1926 July 1 (Box 29)
    - Hartford Courant Daily, Obituary of Henrietta Selden Colt, 1862 January 21 (Box 29)
    - Hays, Henry. Heraldry: Its Origin... NY: E.D. Jenkins, 1856 (Box 29)
    - "Heartsease" Newport, RI news article re: "Old Part Days," house tour, circa 1900 (Box 29)
    - Hitchcock, A. Louise "May in the Revolution" (Box 29)
    - The Huguenot Society of America (Box 29)
    - Japan, embassy et al. (Box 29)
    - Kearsarge Silver Mining Co. stock certificate (Box 29)
    - Knickerbocker Hotel Company, New York (Box 29)
    - LeClerc, Charles, Les Malheurs d'un Petit Oiseau (juvenile) (Box 29)
    - Lehigh Coal Exchange (Box 29)
    - Liberty Loan (World War I) advertisements, 1917-1919 (Box 29)
    - Martha Washington Reception and Tea Party program and clippings, 1875 (Box 29)
    - Merrymount Press New Year's Greeting, 1918 (Box 29)
    - Metropolitan Opera House, Performance in honor of the King and Queen of the Belgians, 1919 October 25 (Box 29)
    - Newport Historical Society Bulletin, 1963 (Box 29)
    - Newport, Rhode Island - Miantonomi Memorial Dedication, 1929 (Box 29)
    - Newport Historical Society Bulletin, references Mrs. C.L.F. Robinson, 1936 July (Box 29)
    - Norseman" (yacht) (Box 29)
    - "Oldport Recipes" (cookbook, Newport, RI) (Box 29)
    - "One Fish Ball" (Box 29)
    - Order of Americans of Armorial Ancestry (Box 29)
    - Perry, Benjamin - historical information (Box 29)
    - Philadelphia Guano Co. (Box 29)
      - Revere House (Boston) bill of fare, 1852 October 25 (Box 29)
    - Portsmouth & Concord Railroad (Box 29)
    - Lt. Caldwell Colt Robinson Post, Hartford CT, 1919 (Box 29)
    - Sachs Laboratories Inc., Hartford Connecticut stock certificate (Box 29)
    - Savarona (yacht) (Box 29)
    - Scientific American vol. IV no.24, 1861 June 15 (Box 29)
    - Silhouette - Bearded man in top hat (Colt?), two deer (Hart?) (Box 29)
    - Shattuck Boat Club (Lake Penacook) (Box 29)
    - Sheffield, Charlie "In memoriam" (Box 29)
    - Some War Songs of Uncle Sam and His Allies (Box 29)
    - Spring Mountain Coal Co. (Box 29)
    - Stowe, Harriet Beacher Poem (copy) (Box 29)
    - Sultan Rug Fastener (Hfd) - sample (Box 29)
    - Titanic news, 1912 (Box 29)
    - Trinity Church (Newport, RI) (Box 29)
    - Trinity College (Hartford, Conn) (Box 29)
    - Twilight Sleep Association (Box 29)
    - Mrs. Samuel Colt - president of Union for Home Work, news article regarding Union for Home Work dedication of new building with address by The Honorable Henry C. Robinson, 1884 October 16 (Box 29)
    - Union and Titusville Rail Road Company (Box 29)
    - United States Navy, citation for "Eyes for the Navy" issued to Mrs CLF Robinson, signed by Franklin D. Roosevelt, Asst. Sec. of Navy, 1919 (Box 29)
    - USS Constitution, USS Constellation (Box 29)
    - USS Toucey (Box 29)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars post 254, Hartford, Dedication Lt. Caldwell Colt Robinson Post, 1938 (Box 29)
    - Victoria (Queen of England), stationery sample (Box 29)
    - Wallingford (Connecticut) Town Hall, Playbill, 1875 December 18 (Box 29)
    - Washington Commentary (Hartford) Ribbon, 1873 (Box 29)
    - Waters, Lilly printed poems (Box 29)
    - Whitaker's Anatomical Model (defective) (Box 29)
    - Wildbader Sommer Theater playbill no.41, 1877 June 29 (Box 29)
    - Yale University Convocation in honor of Marshall Foch, 1921 (Box 29)
    - World War I and Yale Alumni newspaper clippings (Box 29)
    - Robinson family cards and letters, 1740, 1903-1934 (Box 30)
    - Sigourney, L.H. printed elegies (Box 30)
    - Russian language poetry pamphlet titled Dukhovno-Nravstvennyia pesnopenia by Lomonosova, Derzhavina, and Karamzina, Moscow, 1856 (Box 30)
    - St Mark's Church (Augusta, Maine) Hetty B. Hart (Box 30)
    - Church of the Good Shepherd (Hartford, Connecticut) (Box 30)
    - St John's Church, Hartford, Connecticut vestry (Box 30)
    - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey "Little Charlie: A Lament" (Box 30)
    - Colt, Samuel - Calling card (Box 30)
    - Colt, Samuel - Coat of arms (Box 30)
  - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey - Letter to Edmund (Box 30)
  - Colt-Robinson family letters, clippings, and legal papers, including the wills of Elizabeth H. Colt and Francis Robinson, 1905-1955; 2 (Box 30)
  - Unidentified correspondence, undated (Box 30)
  - Wills, 1895, 1957 (Box 30)
  - Frost-Robinson letters and clippings, 2 (Box 30)
  - Estate, mostly F. De Groot Robinson, also C.L.F. Robinson (Box 30)
  - Unidentified financial ledger, 1826-1838; 2 (Box 30)
  - Postcards (Box 31)
  - Postcards (Box 32)
  - Photographs, 13 (Box 33)
  - Photographs, 3 (Box 34)
  - Printed broadsides with views of Moscow and the Colt manufacturing facility, Hartford, undated (Box 35)
  - Books
    - Selections from Various Sources - Sigourney (Box A)
    - Schooner Gaspee 1772 Barlett (Box A)
    - Memory of Pont-y-tu-Prydd (Box A)
    - The Splendor Stays - Marguerite Allis (Box A)
    - Translation-- Wilhelm Meister-Carlyle volumes 1-2 (Box A)
    - Thirty Thousand Miles with Wanderer - Robinson (Box A)
    - Roba di Roma volumes 1-2 (Box A)
    - U.S. Infantry and Rifle Tactics, Complete, 1861 (Box A)
    - Whisper to a Bride (Box A)
    - Common Book of Prayer (Box A)